#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Translator and content manager

National Geographic - The Walt Disney Company (Remote), February 2017-Present

- Translation (EN>ES) of news articles within strict deadlines.
- Proposal and selection of locally-relevant daily news.
- Content management and editing through a CMS (Drupal).
- Subtitling and translation of educational videos for the National Geographic website and social media, and promotional videos for Nat Geo Channel's documentaries and series.
- Translation of partner content for brands such as Rolex, Nespresso and Reckitt Benckiser.
- Translation and proofreading of marketing presentations for Disney+, Fox Networks Group and National Geographic following company styling.
- Coordinating localisation of environmental projects, such as Planet or Plastic, Pristine Seas, Big Cats Initiative, and Okavango Wilderness Project.
- Linguistinc and functional testing of apps and promotional microsites.

#### Translator and transcreator

National Geographic Expeditions (Remote), May 2019-Present

- Translation (EN>ES) and proofreading of travel itineraries, tour information and guides.
- Transcreation of marketing newsletters to increase brand engagement.
- Transcreation of blog posts for marketing purposes.

# Translator and proofreader

University of Santiago de Compostela (Remote), June-July 2020

• Translation of research studies (ES>EN) about communication and political sciences published in scientific journals.

#### Translator and proofreader

University of Vigo (Remote), Dec 2018-Feb 2020

• Translation of academic articles (ES>EN) to be published in specialized magazines on the topics of corporate communication and disinformation, public relations, marketing and communications.

#### **Localisation specialist**

Jublo (Remote), January-March 2020

- Post-editing machine translations (EN>ES) for a digital advertising project.
- Communicating on a daily basis with the localisation project manager for asset allocation.

#### **Translator**

Vegware (Remote), September 2019

- Translation (EN>ES) and proofreading of Vegware product descriptions for the latest edition of their Spanish-language catalogue.
- Liaising with the Communications department to establish the parameters of content localisation.

# MARCELA TORRES SUÁREZ

Translator and content editor

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a driven and ambitious professional with four years of experience in the digital media, translation and localisation industry, working with creative content on a daily basis to help my clients achieve their goals. I have a consistent track record serving as a mediator between cultures and facilitating communication.

As a freelancer, I have learned to become self-reliant and impeccably organised in order to manage my own projects and to deliver concise solutions for my clients

I am confident I can thrive in any position I am placed in.

## **CONTACT**

Edinburgh
07542502055
marcela.torress@outlook.es
LinkedIn
mttraducciones.com

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish (Native)
- Galician (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- French (Conversational

### Interpreter and translator

Simetrías Fundación Internacional (Madrid), May-December 2017

- Interpreting (EN < > ES) during the conference European Testimony Tour "From Africa to Europe", focusing on female genital mutilation.
- Interpreting from English into Spanish and viceversa during an event about women's empowerment ran by Asociación Karibu.
- Translating (Spanish into English) session reports within the AFTER project.

#### Interpreter

Federación Española de Universidades Populares (Madrid), June 2017

• Interpreting (EN < > ES) at the International Conference for the MUPYME Project: Employment and Women in the 21st century in Europe.

### Telephone interpreter

thebigword (Remote), December 2016-February 2017

- Telephone interpreting (English into Spanish and vice versa) for UK government agencies such as HMRC, HM Treasury and DWP.
- Telephone interpreting for Universal Credit phone line.
- Telephone interpreting for NHS hospitals and GP offices.
- Telephone interpreting for law firms.

### **Digital Media intern**

Fox Networks Group (Madrid), May-September 2016

- Acting as a point of contact for other Digital Media departments in European countries, Israel, and South Africa.
- Attending meetings and calls, and note-taking.
- Editorial calendar management.
- Translating and proofreading editorial content.
- CMS management for Fox TV and National Geographic Channel.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Autonomous University of Barcelona**

Master's in Audiovisual Translation, September 2018-May 2019

- Subtitling for the deaf and hard of hearing.
- Audio-description for blind and partially sighted people.
- Translation of subtitles and dubbing scripts for series and films.
- Video game localisation.

## **Autonomous University of Madrid**

Bachelor's degree in Translation and Interpreting, September 2013-May 2017

- Translation and interpreting from English into Spanish and vice versa.
- Economic, scientific, legal and technical translation.
- Scientific and medical translation from French into Spanish.

# Heriot-Watt University (Erasmus placement)

Bachelor's degree in Translation and Interpreting, September 2014-May 2015

- Translation and interpreting from English/French into Spanish.
- Languages applied to marketing and business administration.
- British culture and society studies.

# ADDITIONAL TRAINING AND CERTIFICATES

- Introduction to Project
   Management (Polytechnic
   University of Valencia- in progress)
- Digital Skills: Digital Marketing (Adecco)
- SEO Mini Course for Beginners (ClickSlice)
- Google Analytics for Beginners (Google Analytics Academy)
- IELTS International English Language Testing System (Band score: 8.5/C2 CEFR level)
- Certificate in Advanced English (Pass with Merit/C1 CEFR level)

## **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- Content Management Systems (Drupal, WordPress)
- Microsoft Office
- CAT tools (Trados, Memsource
- Project management
- Copywriting
- Teamwork
- Multitasking
- Intercultural communication

# VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

- Packer (Empty Kitchens, Full Hearts)
- Erasmus Teaching Assistan (Heriot-Watt University)

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon reques